<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Jax on Gabe&#39;s Gulch</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/jax/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jax on Gabe&#39;s Gulch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.150.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/jax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic Model Predictive Control</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-11-18-stochastic-mpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-11-18-stochastic-mpc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many applications of optimization and control are performed in a deterministic setting. That is, the quantities of the problem such as the state variables, control variables, and or parameters of a model are treated as fixed known values. This assumption may be reasonable in applications such as robotics, but in others such as resource allocation, we may need to incorporate the uncertainty of various quantities in order to compute the &lt;strong&gt;expectation&lt;/strong&gt; of the objective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reproducing Uber&#39;s Marketplace Optimization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-09-15-marketplace-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-09-15-marketplace-optimization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Uber allocates money across different regions and programs to incentivize riders and drivers to use Uber products. This incentive structure ultimately influences the market. This leads to the natural question of &amp;ldquo;how much to allocate to each city and which program&amp;rdquo; to maximize business objectives? Uber has a finite amount of money that must be allocated accordingly. Given a total budget of say, $1,000,000, how should it be divied up amongst the cities and programs?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[WIP] It&#39;s About Making Decisions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-08-08-its-about-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-08-08-its-about-decisions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Concepts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data science is largely about making decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disappointed with the Bayesian community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How PPLs can be a powerful tool for sequential decision making under uncertainty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is sequential decision making?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Energy modeling demo (part 1).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For companies applying data science and machine learning, it is largely about making decisions—how much inventory should we stock?, how much resources should we allocate?, what parameters should be used for this manufacturing machine?—To arrive at such a decision, analyzing historical data and developing some sort of model is often required. This is the easy part. How this model and analysis is used in downstream systems to make optimal decisions is the hard part. The most impactful data scientists at a company are developing and deploying methods and systems to make decisions, not to develop the next Deep XG Random Effects Boosted Neural Tree Networks™ that achieves a super &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; evaluation metric. This post will be the first in a series of posts on sequential decision making under uncertainty. We will use probabilistic programming languages (PPLs) to model uncertainty and then embed these models in a sequential decision making framework to make optimal decisions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
